outtask.com 2015-03-16

# Concur Technologies Privacy Policy - Concur

**Concur Technologies, Inc. Privacy Policy**

**NOTICE OF CHANGES to Concur.com visitors: Concur has made changes to its privacy policy in an effort to better describe how it collects, uses, and shares its information. Please contact us by emailing**[ **privacy-request@concur.com**](mailto:privacy-request@concur.com) **with any questions or concerns about these changes.**

Last Updated: August 8, 2014

This Privacy Policy (“Policy”) summarizes the various ways that Concur Technologies, Inc. and its subsidiaries, and other affiliated and related companies ("Concur" or "we" or “us”) use the information you provide to us or we gather from you while you access or use the Web sites of Concur, including concur.com (collectively, "Sites") our mobile applications (“App”), and our related sites and online services (collectively, the (“Services”) (however accessed and/or used, whether via personal computers, mobile devices or otherwise "Device"). It is our goal to provide you with information that is tailored to your individual needs and, at the same time, protect respect your privacy. The United States Department of Commerce and the European Commission have agreed on a set of data protection principles and frequently asked questions to enable United States companies to satisfy the requirement under EU law that adequate protection be given to personal information transferred from the EEA to the United States (the "U.S.-EU Safe Harbor"). The United States Department of Commerce and the Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner of Switzerland (“FDPIC”) have agreed on a similar set of principles and frequently asked questions to enable United States companies to satisfy the requirement under Swiss law that adequate protection be given to personal information transferred from Switzerland to the United States (the “U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor”). Consistent with its commitment to protect personal privacy, Concur complies with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor as set forth by the United States Department of Commerce and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor (collectively the “Safe Harbor Principles”) regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from the EU and Switzerland. Concur’s Safe Harbor certification can be found at <http://web.ita.doc.gov/safeharbor/shlist.nsf/webPages/safe+harbor+list>. For more information about the Safe Harbor Principles, please visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Website at <http://export.gov/safeharbor/>.

Please read this Policy carefully. Your access to or use of any part of the Services will constitute your notice about our collection, use, and disclosure of your information in accordance with this Policy. If you do not wish for us to collect, use, and disclose your information in accordance with this Policy, please do not access or use the Services. This Policy does not cover information collected elsewhere, including, without limitation, offline or on sites linked to through the Services. We may add to or amend this Policy with other notices. We may also post different privacy statements for some Services and when we do so, this Policy does not apply. For example, separate policies and terms apply to information collected through our concur.com site and platform or our other mobile applications.

This Policy applies solely to information collected by us through the Services and does not apply to any third-party activities, including third party websites linked from our Services, third party social networking platforms or features we make available through our Services, or third-party ads displayed on our Services. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such third-parties. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of those third parties.

INFORMATION COLLECTED

We collect information from you in various ways when you use our Sites. We collect information you directly provide to us. For example, we collect your name, home location, billing or mailing address, email address, postal address, phone number, fax number, demographics, preference information and other information you provide us on our Sites. We also collect credit card numbers if you purchase services on our Sites or use services that reconcile your credit card charges. We may also obtain information from other sources and combine that with information we collect on our Sites.

When you visit our Sites, some information is automatically collected. For example, when you visit our Sites, your computer's operating system, Internet Protocol (IP) address, Device Identifier, access times, browser type, device type, domain name, access times, duration of visit, referring URL, platform, new and repeat information, time stamp and language, and referring Web site addresses are logged automatically. We also collect information about your usage and activity on our Sites. A Device Identifier is a number that is automatically assigned to your Device used to access the Services, and allows us to identify your Device by its Device Identifier.  

**Tracking Technologies.**   We may use various technologies to automatically collect Device Identifiers, and other information about you **("Tracking Technologies")**. These Tracking Technologies work in different ways, for example some may be downloaded to your Device and others may set or modify settings on your Device.  The following are examples of a few of the methods that may be used to collect information include, without limitation, the following (and subsequent technology and methods hereafter developed):

**Cookies.** We may automatically collect information using "cookies." Cookies are small data files stored on your hard drive by a Web site. Among other things, cookies help us improve our Sites and your experience. We use cookies to see which areas and features are popular and to count visits to our Sites. If you set your browser not to accept cookies or if you reject a cookie (your help screen or manual should tell you how to do this), it may affect certain features or services of our Sites.

**Web Beacons.** We may collect information using Web beacons. Web beacons are electronic images that may be used on our Sites or in our emails. We use Web beacons to deliver cookies, count visits, understand usage and campaign effectiveness and to tell if an email has been opened and acted upon.

**ETag, or entity tag.**   A feature of the cache in browsers.  It is an opaque identifier assigned by a web server to a specific version of a resource found at a URL.  If the resource content at that URL ever changes, a new and different ETag is assigned.  Used in this manner, ETags are a form of Device Identifier.  ETag tracking may generate unique tracking values even where the consumer blocks HTTP, Flash, and HTML5 cookies.

**Location-identifying Technologies.**   Additionally, the Services may use GPS (global positioning systems) software and other location-based technologies such as iBeacons to locate you so we may verify your location, deliver you relevant content based on your location, as well as allow you to share your location to other users as part of the services we provide via the Services.  Upon downloading the App, we determine your approximate and/or exact location information to provide location-based services.  In addition to traditional GPS location-based services, some of the retailers and others we work with may install other types of location tracking technology, such as low power Bluetooth, wifi, radio transmitters, or other devices in physical locations. These technologies emit a signal that the App can detect to pinpoint your proximity to those locations (such as how close you are to security checkpoints, gates, terminals, or retail locations and products) or otherwise interact with the App (such as to send you helpful information, offers, and discounts).  To learn more about iBeacons visit Apple’s privacy policy and website.

**Targeting‑Related**.  We may use Tracking Technologies to learn more about you and your preferences and deliver content, including ads that seem relevant to your interests on our Services and third‑party services, based on how you interact with advertisements or content, and/or based on your location and other information about you.  

**Flash LSOs.** When we post videos or other media on our blog, third parties may use local shared objects, also known as Flash cookies, to store your preferences for volume control, or to personalize certain features. Flash cookies are different from browser cookies because of the amount of, type of, and how data is stored. Cookie management tools provided by your browser will not remove Flash cookies. To learn how to manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies click here:

<http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html#117118>

**Third Party Advertisements.** We and our third party partners may use information collected using third-party cookies and Web beacons on our Services and in our emails to deliver ads about our Services displayed to you on third-party websites and applications. We also may use cookie information and other methods to know when you return to our Services after visiting these third-party websites and applications. We use this and other information about you to try to understand your interests and show you relevant advertising about products and services that may interest you. Our third party partners may also use this information for third party advertising as described above. We may use third parties to serve ads in our Services. These third parties may automatically collect information about your use of the Service, visits to our Site and other Web sites, your IP address, your ISP, the browser you use to visit our Site (but not your name, address, email address or telephone number). They do this using cookies, clear gifs or other technologies. Information collected may be used, among other things, to deliver advertising targeted to your interests and to better understand the usage and visitation of our Site and the other sites tracked by these third parties. This Policy does not apply to, and we are not responsible for, cookies or clear gifs in third party ads, and we encourage you to check the privacy policies of advertisers and/or ad services to learn about their use of cookies and other technology. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, click here: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/consumer/opt_out.asp>.

USE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT

We use personal information collected through our Sites for purposes described in this Policy or disclosed to you on our Sites or in connection with our services. For example, we may use your information to:

  * operate and improve our Sites and services;
  * personalize and customize your Site experience, content, marketing, and recommendations across all our Services, including to target content on our Services to more closely match your interests or your location;
  * process and deliver contest entries and rewards;
  * respond to your comments and questions and provide customer service;
  * provide and deliver products and to send you related information, including confirmations, invoices, technical notices, updates, security alerts, and support and administrative messages;
  * register you for events and training;
  * send you information related to your requests and purchases, including confirmations, invoices, technical notices, updates, security alerts, and support and administrative messages;
  * communicate with you about new contests, promotions and rewards, upcoming events, and other news about products and services offered by Concur and our selected partners;
  * link or combine with other personal information we get from third parties, to help understand your needs and provide you with better service.

Concur may store and process personal information in the United States and other countries.

SHARING OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

When you use the Service, your personal information and your travel information will be shared with the third parties you designate for access to such information including other companies, websites, mobile applications, your friends, relatives, and business associates. Depending upon the type of access you grant to such third parties, they may also be permitted to edit the information you have provided to us and to designate others to access and edit such information. You may change these settings as to who has access to your information by going to your account settings and then changing your publishing options.

You may choose to display certain information you give us in your public profile. Our Site also offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you choose to share in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others. In addition, you may be able to send your location information via the Services to other Services users.  You should consider the pros and cons involved in disclosing your location information to us and to other people.  Where a user of the Services requests that their location information be revealed to other persons, the user will be provided options for managing sharing services, which may be through third party services such as through Twitter and Facebook.  We are not responsible for the acts, omissions or policies of such third parties.

In general, most of your travel related information, such as upcoming destinations and travel statistics, is displayed only to other users of the Service to whom you have specifically connected as part of your Concur / TripIt network. You can change your privacy settings to designate which types of information are shared and with whom by visiting the [Profile and Privacy](https://www.tripit.com/account/edit/section/your_profile) page. You may also post information about your travel plans or current travel status through your Concur / TripIt connections or other social networking connections or otherwise instruct the Service to automatically provide such information to other users of the Service and with your social networking connections.

We do not share your personal information with third parties other than as follows:

  * in an aggregated form that does not directly identify you;
  * with your consent, for example, when you agree to our sharing your information with other third parties for their own marketing uses subject to their privacy policies;
  * with your employer if you are participating in a Concur service provided through your employer;
  * with third party vendors, consultants and other service providers who are working on our behalf and need access to your information to carry out their work for us;
  * with third party websites, services and mobile applications you authorize to link to your Concur service as part of their service to you;
  * to (i) comply with laws or to respond to lawful requests and legal process, (ii) to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal or suspected illegal activities, (iii) to protect the rights and property of Concur our agents, members, and others including to enforce our agreements, policies and terms of use or (iv) in an emergency to protect the personal safety of Concur, its customers, or any person;
  * in connection with a corporate transaction, such as a divestiture, merger, consolidation, sale of company assets, financing or acquisition of all or a portion of our business to another company.
  * from time to time, we also may share general information about our Services, users, and visitors such as the number of visitors, aggregate and/or non-personally identifiable demographic and travel data, etc., with third parties (including with your employer if your account was provided through your employer).

SECURITY OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

We maintain data handling and storage practices and procedures that are designed to promote the integrity and confidentiality of the personally identifiable information. No method of transmission over the Internet or method of electronic storage is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information in an effort to prevent loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

YOUR INFORMATION CHOICES AND CHANGES

We think that you benefit from a more personalized experience when we know more about you and your Concur experiences. The nature of our Services depends upon the use of Tracking Technologies for the purposes described above and we require your consent to such uses in order to use the Services, except that you have the option to change settings on your device and uninstall the Apps.  We are giving you detailed notice of the Tracking Technologies and your limited choices regarding them so that your consent is meaningfully informed. In some cases you can limit the information you provide to us, and you can limit the communications that we send to you. You may opt out of receiving promotional emails from Concur by following the instructions in those emails. If you are registered on any of our Sites, you may login and make certain changes to your information in your account. You may also send requests about your preferences and changes to your information by emailing [privacy-request@concur.com](mailto:privacy-request@concur.com). If you opt out, we may still send you non-promotional emails, such as emails about your accounts or our ongoing business relations. Additionally, if you are participating in a Concur service through your employer, your employer may make changes to information on your behalf. If you wish to cancel your account, modify your information, or request that we no longer use your information to provide you the Service, contact us at [support@concur.com](mailto:support@concur.com).

**Email Choices.** You can manage your email preferences by updating your profile settings. You can also unsubscribe from promotional emails by: (1) following the unsubscribe instructions in our emails; or (2) emailing us at [support@concur.com](mailto:support@concur.com). You may update your email preferences from time to time. Please note that even if you unsubscribe from promotional email messages, we may still need to contact you with important transactional information related to your account and your use of the Service. For example, even if you have unsubscribed from our email messages, we will still send you emails confirming emails relating directly to an itinerary or travel profile created through the Service confirming registration.

**SMS Choices.** You may manage the SMS alerts regarding flight delays, gate changes, and other alert information specific to your itinerary sent by the Service to your mobile device by following the opt-out instructions in each SMS message.

**Do Not Track.** We may not recognize or respond to every type of “do not track” signal or other mechanisms that provide consumers the ability to exercise choice regarding the collection of personally identifiable information about an individual consumer’s online activities over time and across third-party websites or online services, but we give you certain choices about how we collect personally identifiable information as described in this Policy. Many Web browsers are set to accept cookies by default. If you prefer, you can usually choose to set your browser to remove cookies and to reject cookies. If you choose to remove cookies or reject cookies, this could affect certain features or services of our Site including certain opt-out cookies. Cookie management tools provided by your browser usually will not remove Flash cookies. To learn how to manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies click here:<http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html#117118> (or in the EU <http://www.youronlinechoices.com/>).

We encourage you to review the privacy policies of our third party advertisers and analytics service providers (<http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/>) to learn about your choices about information they collect from you. In addition, the [Network Advertising Initiative offers](http://www.networkadvertising.org/) information about some of the Internet advertising companies we may use, including how to opt-out of interest based advertising they deliver. To opt-out of Google Analytics web tracking you can download [Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).

Further, third parties may associate Tracking Technologies with our Service and in physical locations that enable the interaction with App when your Device is close.  We may not control those Tracking Technologies and in such event, we are not responsible for them. However, you consent to potentially encountering third party Tracking Technologies in connection with use of our Services and accept that our statements under this Privacy Policy do not apply to the Tracking Technologies or practices of such third parties except as explicitly stated (e.g., your consent). 

CHANGES TO THIS POLICY

Concur may change this Policy from time to time without notice to you other than posting the revised policy on our Services. If we make any changes to this Policy, we will change the "Last Updated" date above. Any changes will be effective immediately upon the posting of the revised Policy and your use of our Service indicates your consent to the privacy policy posted at the time of use. However, Concur will not use your previously collected personal information in a manner materially different than what was stated at the time it was collected without your consent. 

ENFORCEMENT

If you have any questions about this Policy or to file any complaint regarding this policy, please contact us at the following address:  
Concur Technologies, Inc.  
601 – 108th Avenue NE, Suite 1000

Bellevue, WA 98004  
USA  
Attention: [privacy-request@concur.com](mailto:privacy-request@concur.com)  
Telephone: (888) 883-8411

Concur will investigate and attempt to resolve complaints and disputes regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of personal information by referencing the privacy principles stated in this Policy. For complaints that cannot be resolved, Concur has agreed to participate in the following dispute resolution procedures in the investigation and resolution of complaints to resolve disputes pursuant to the Safe Harbor Principles: (1) For disputes involving all personal information received by Concur from Switzerland, Concur has agreed to cooperate with the Swiss FDPIC; (2) For disputes involving employment-related personal information received by Concur from the EEA, Concur has agreed to cooperate with the independent dispute resolution service provided by the Data Protection Authorities in the EEA and to participate in the dispute resolution procedures of the panel established by the European Data Protection Authorities; and (3) For all other disputes, you can contact TRUSTe on-line at <http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint> or at the address below. If you are faxing or mailing TRUSTe to lodge a complaint, you must include the following information: the name of company, the alleged privacy violation, your contact information, and whether you would like the particulars of your complaint shared with the company. For information about TRUSTe or the operation of TRUSTe's dispute resolution process, [click here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint&url=) or request this information from TRUSTe at any of the addresses listed above. The TRUSTe dispute resolution process shall be conducted in English.

Watchdog Complaints  
TRUSTe  
55 2nd Street, 2nd Floor  
San Francisco, CA 94105  
Telephone: (415) 520-3400  
Facsimile: (415) 520-3420
